Finding Aid of the Andrew Hamilton Papers LSC.1227
UCLA Library Special Collections
Andrew Hamilton papers
1940-1974
UCLA Library Special Collections
Hamilton, Andrew
LSC.1227
66.0 linear feet (132 boxes)
Andrew Jackson Hamilton (1911-1976) was a U.S. Navy public information officer on the West Coast and in the Pacific on the staff of Admiral Chester W. Nimitz during World War II, and public information manager (1946-60) and Public Affairs Officer (1960-75) at UCLA. He helped to organize Naval Reserve Public Relations Company 11-2 (1949), wrote more than a thousand articles for some 75 magazines, and co-authored UCLA on the move (1969) with John B. Jackson. In 1973, Hamilton and his wife were awarded the University Service Award. The collection consists of mostly subject files containing manuscripts, published articles, clippings, and research material related to Hamilton's writing, his service in the U.S. Navy during World War II, and his career as UCLA Public Affairs officer.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Mrs. Andrew J. Hamilton, 1976.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9914707293606533
Biography
Andrew Jackson Hamilton was born on April 18, 1911 in Riverside, California; BA, UCLA, 1935; became a reporter and feature writer for two years with the Los Angeles times; U.S. Navy public information officer on the West Coast and in the Pacific on the staff of Admiral Chester W. Nimitz during World War II; public information manager (1946-60) and Public Affairs Officer (1960-75) UCLA; helped to organize Naval Reserve Public Relations Company 11-2 in 1949; wrote more than a thousand articles for some 75 magazines, including Saturday evening post, Collier's, and Science digest; co-authored UCLA on the move (1969) with John B. Jackson; along with his wife Janice, awarded the University Service Award in 1973; retired in 1975; died on April 8, 1976 in Los Angeles.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of mostly subject files containing manuscripts, published articles, clippings, and research material related to Andrew Hamilton's writing, his service in the U.S. Navy during World War II, and his career as UCLA Public Affairs officer.
Expanded Scope and Content Note
The papers mainly comprise clippings, articles and other research materials for Andrew Hamilton's writing but also include records relating to his service in World War II as a Navy public information officer with Fleet Admiral Nimitz in the Pacific. He was a UCLA graduate of the Class of 1935 and held the position of Public Affairs Officer for many years prior to his retirement from the university in 1975. He contributed as a freelance writer to a number of national magazines and was for some time a reporter and feature writer for the Los Angeles Times.
Related Material
Interview of Andrew J. Hamilton (1966) UCLA public information manager and public affairs officer.
Interview of Andrew J. Hamilton (1972) Research, problems, and writing of the fiftieth anniversary history of UCLA, UCLA on the Move, and the planning and scheduling of events for anniversary celebrations in 1969.
UCLA public affairs officer [oral history transcript] / Andrew J. Hamilton, interviewee. UCLA Oral History Department interview, c1972. Available at Department of Special Collections, UCLA.
Public relations -- Archives.; Authors, American -- 20th century -- Archives.; Hamilton, Andrew, 1911-1976--Archives.; University of California, Los Angeles. Public Affairs--Employees -- Archives
- Acne. (Box 1)
- Adoptions: trans-racial. (Box 1)
- Autonetics. (Box 1)
- Alcoholism (Box 1)
  - General file. (Box 1)
  - Material from companies. (Box 1)
  - Con Edison. (Box 1)
  - Du Pont. (Box 1)
  - Great Northern. (Box 1)
  - Hughes. (Box 1)
  - National Council. (Box 1)
  - Kemper. (Box 1)
  - New York City Transit Authority. (Box 1)
  - Pacific Telephone. (Box 1)
  - Rocketdyne. (Box 1)
  - Union Carbide. (Box 1)
- American Farm School. (Box 2)
- Anthropology. (Box 2)
- Apollo subcontractors. (Box 2)
- Asteroids (Herrick). (Box 2)
- Asimow, Morris (Brazil Project). (Box 2, Box 3)
- Notebook - A New Role Of The University In Overseas Technical Assistance. (Box 3)
- Notebook - Project Picture Report Of The Asimov Industry Project In Ceara, October 1964. (Box 3)
- Bagpipes - Highland Games. (Box 4)
- Bilingual Education. (Box 4)
- Biochemical Individuality. (Box 4)
- Bone Marrow Transplant (BARBA). (Box 4)
- Boredom. (Box 4)
- Brazil. (Box 4)
- Burpee - White Marigold. (Box 5)
- Calligraphy. (Box 5)
- Child amputee prosthetics project. (Box 5)
- Computers (Box 6, Box 7)
  - "Push Button Medicine." (Box 6)
  - Desk calculator at Aerojet-Gen. (Box 6)
  - Stanford. (Box 6)
  - Libraries of future. (Box 7)
- Confidence - young adults (NDI). (Box 7)
- Cornell, Ralph. (Box 7)
- Coughing. (Box 7)
- Cryogenics. (Box 7)
- Deep Canyon desert research. (Box 7)
- Desert travel - Death Valley. (Box 7)
- Diet - Dr. Schauf. (Box 7)
- Direction sports. (Box 7)
- D-M-S-O. (Box 8)
- Dolphins. (Box 8)
- Drowsy driver. (Box 8)
- Drug dodgers. (Box 8)
- Dubnoff school. (Box 8)
- Dummies. (Box 8)
- Dwarfs. (Box 8)
- Eagle Scouts. (Box 8)
- Electric guidance for cars. (Box 9)
  General note
  (See also Boxes 131, 132)
- Epilepsy. (Box 9)
- Exercise (Box 9)
  - Heart rated. (Box 9)
  - At Leisure World. (Box 9)
  - "Limber Up And Live." (Box 9)
- Fabricated foods - Dr. Ross Hume Hall. (Box 9)
- Firemen paramedics. (Box 10)
- First four minutes - Zunin. (Box 10)
- Fish markets (San Pedro). (Box 10)
- Fort Ross. (Box 10)
- Gambling. (Box 10)
- Geothermal power. (Box 10)
- Grandjury (Sue Young). (Box 10)
- Graphite composites. (Box 11)
- Heimlich maneuver. (Box 11)
- Hunter, Madeline C. (Box 11)
- Inventions. (Box 12)
- IRS small claims court. (Box 12)
- Israel - Afforestation. (Box 12)
- Jackson, Admiral Richard H. (Box 12)
- Juvenile traffic division. (Box 12)
- Learning Wall. (Box 12)
- Jet Propulsion Laboratory. (Box 13)
- "Kingdom Of Could Be You." (Box 13)
- Live to be 100. (Box 13)
- Maps and map makers - Middle East. (Box 13)
- Microsurgery. (Box 13)
- Military - industrial complex. (Box 14)
- Miller, Julius Sumner. (Box 14)
- Miscellaneous - reprints, etc. (Box 14)
- Music. (Box 14)
- National Education Task Force De La Raza. (Box 14)
- Nobile, Fredrick Blaine. (Box 15)
- Noise. (Box 15)
- Old Shep. (Box 15)
- Oldendorf, Admiral J.B. (Box 15)
- Orange County consortium - career education project. (Box 15)
- P.I.E. (Los Angeles city schools). (Box 15)
- Poisons - in the home and garden. (Box 15)
- Problem solving (Moshe Rubenstein). (Box 16)
- Project Catchup. (Box 16)
- Prosthetics. (Box 16)
- Reader's Digest research. (Box 16, Box 17)
  - [No further description available]. (Box 16)
  - Fog seeding. (Box 16)
  - Viva. (Box 17)
- Schick stop - smoking centers. (Box 17)
- Seven steps to good health, longevity. (Box 17)
- Shipbuilding. (Box 17)
- Smarter than you think (Dr. Lissy Jarvik). (Box 17)
- Soochow. (Box 17)
- Soybeans. (Box 18)
- Sugar. (Box 18)
- Superior Court in Los Angeles. (Box 18)
- Systems engineering. (Box 18)
- Tissue culture. (Box 19)
- Topgun. (Box 19)
- Travel (Box 19, Box 20, Box 21, Box 22)
  - Europe, ideas, articles. (Box 19)
  - Europe, Thessaluniki, 1969. (Box 19)
  - Europe, Istanbul, 1969. (Box 20)
  - Europe, Cave art, Spain, France, 1971. (Box 20)
  - Europe, Andora, 1971. (Box 20)
  - Europe, Spain (Paradores), 1971. (Box 20)
  - Africa, 1973. (Box 20)
  - Spain, 1975. (Box 20)
  - Australia, New Zealand, 1974. (Box 20)
  - Study tours. (Box 21)
- Tule elk. (Box 21)
- Turpin, Dr. James Project Concern. (Box 21)
- Turpin, Mollie. (Box 22)
- Vampire bat. (Box 22)
- Vandalism in schools. (Box 22)
- Viking mission. (Box 22)
- Vitamin C. (Box 23)
- "Vocal Suicide" - Dr. Morton Copper. (Box 23)
- Volcanoes. (Box 23)
- Weisgal - Weizmann Institute. (Box 23)
- Windmills. (Box 23)
- Winemaking. (Box 24)
- Wooden, John. (Box 24)
- Workman - eucalyptus tree. (Box 24)
- Wycliffe - Bible translators. (Box 24)
- Yamamoto - Y-Square. (Box 24)
- Agriculture. (Box 25)
- Animals - birds. (Box 25)
- Community projects. (Box 25)
- Crime. (Box 25)
- Education. (Box 25)
- History. (Box 25)
- Hollywood. (Box 25)
- Industrial. (Box 25)
- Medicine. (Box 25)
- Military. (Box 26)
- Miscellaneous. (Box 26)
- Nutrition. (Box 26)
- Out-of-doors. (Box 26)
- Personalities. (Box 26)
- Religion. (Box 26)
- Science. (Box 26)
- Sports. (Box 26)
- Travel. (Box 27)
- Women - children - family. (Box 27)
- School bosses. (Box 27)
- Shelf Lots - "Suburbia On The Shelf." (Box 27)
- Rejected Queries, v.d. (Box 27)
  - Pre-1951. (Box 27)
  - Post-1951. (Box 27)
- Rejected Manuscripts, v.d. (Box 28)
  - Pre-1945. (Box 28)
  - 1946-1951. (Box 28)
  - 1951. (Box 28)
- Published Articles, pre-1945-1976 (Box 29, Box 30, Box 31, Box 32)
  - 1976-1970. (Box 29)
  - 1969-1962. (Box 30)
  - 1961-1950. (Box 31)
  - 1949-pre-1945. (Box 32)
- Information about freelancing. (Box 32)
- Army, Navy commissions, miscellaneous. (Box 32)
- Navy Orders, 1941-1965 (Box 32, Box 33)
  - (World War II)., 1941-1946 (Box 32)
  - 1946-1949. (Box 32)
  - 1950-1954. (Box 33)
  - 1955-1959. (Box 33)
  - 1960-1964. (Box 33)
  - 1965. (Box 33)
- Navy Correspondence Courses, 1949-1969. (Box 33, Box 34, Box 35)
  - Military Law, 1949. (Box 33)
  - Navy Regulations, 1950. (Box 34)
  - Island Governments, 1950. (Box 34)
  - Navy Orientation, 1951. (Box 34)
  - Foundations of National Power, 1952. (Box 34)
  - Seamanship, 1952-1953. (Box 34)
  - Uniform Code of Military Justice, 1953. (Box 34)
  - Leadership, 1953-1954. (Box 34)
  - Logistics, 1954-1955. (Box 34)
  - Public Information, 1955-1956. (Box 34)
  - Naval Intelligence, 1956-1957, 1957-1958. (Box 34)
  - Organization for National Security, 1958. (Box 34)
  - Personal Administration, 1958-1959. (Box 34)
  - Arctic Operations, 1959. (Box 34)
  - Education and Training (Part 1), 1960. (Box 34)
  - Industrial Relations, 1961-1962. (Box 34)
  - Introduction to Space Technology, 1962. (Box 34)
  - Security of Classified Information, 1963. (Box 34)
  - Radiological Defense, 1963. (Box 34)
  - General Oceanography, 1964. (Box 34)
  - Financial Management in the Navy, 1965. (Box 34)
  - Economics of Defense, 1966. (Box 35)
  - Disaster Control, 1966. (Box 35)
  - Naval Aviation, 1967. (Box 35)
  - MSTS, 1969. (Box 35)
  - Naval Communications, 1969. (Box 35)
  - Investigations, Claims. (Box 35)
- Navy Admiralty Law, 1970. (Box 35)
- Naval War College, May 28-June 10, 1961. (Box 35)
- Foreign Service Institute. (Box 35)
- Research Material. (Box 36)
- Admission to alma mater. (Box 36)
- Aerial photography. (Box 36)
- Aerojet. (Box 36)
- Aeronutronic. (Box 36)
- Aerospace Corporation. (Box 36)
- AFRS. (Box 37)
- Aging. (Box 37)
- Aho, Ilma Ruth. (Box 37)
- AIESEC. (Box 37)
- Alcoholism. (Box 37)
- Alpha helix. (Box 37)
- Amino acids. (Box 37)
- Andy Anderson and Middle Fork. (Box 38)
- Antique cars - Frank Stokes. (Box 38)
- Arbitration (American Association of). (Box 38)
- Arabian horses. (Box 39)
- Archery. (Box 39)
- Art center school. (Box 39)
- Artificial Roses. (Box 39)
- Athletes. (Box 40)
- Atkinson, J. Robert (Braille Institute). (Box 40)
- Audubon Center of Southern California. (Box 40)
- Automobile crash research - UCLA. (Box 40)
- Automobile hospital. (Box 40)
- Automobile statistics (computer system). (Box 40)
- Automobile stunt shows. (Box 40)
- Avalanches. (Box 41)
- Aviation. (Box 41)
- Aviation - instrumentation. (Box 41)
- Bare hand repair. (Box 41)
- Bat cave. (Box 41)
- Beale. (Box 42)
- Becket. (Box 42)
- Better Fishing Incorporated. (Box 42)
- Biological clocks. (Box 42)
- Biotechnology. (Box 42)
- Bio-luminiscence. (Box 42)
- Blue collar colleges. (Box 42)
- Books for the blind. (Box 42)
- Bow hunting. (Box 42)
- Bowen, Ira Sprague (Palomar observatory directory). (Box 42)
- Bowron, Fletcher. (Box 42)
- Brastoff, Sascha (ceramics). (Box 42)
- Bristlecone pines. (Box 43)
- Brownell tours. (Box 43)
- Bubonic plague. (Box 43)
- Buckley schools. (Box 43)
- Burbank story. (Box 43)
- Burkey fish screens. (Box 43)
- Business menu's art institute. (Box 44)
- Bynum, Lindley. (Box 44)
- Calculators. (Box 44)
- Calico. (Box 44)
- California water project. (Box 44)
- Careers. (Box 44)
- Cement. (Box 45)
- Chaffee, Dorsey, Jack. (Box 45)
- Charity cheats. (Box 45)
- Childbirth and hypnosis. (Box 45)
- Christian ministry in the national parks. (Box 45)
- Chino-horses. (Box 46)
- Circus doctor. (Box 46)
- Cities of U.S. (Box 46)
- City of Hope. (Box 46)
- Clothes - distributed by Navajos. (Box 46)
- Clyde, Norman. (Box 47)
- Clymer, Floyd D. (Box 47)
- Coal mine flooding. (Box 47)
- Coast Guard (Box 47, Box 48)
  - [No further description available]. (Box 47)
  - Auxiliary. (Box 48)
  - Aids to navigation. (Box 48)
  - Bering Sea. (Box 48)
  - Ice patrol. (Box 48)
- Coffee drinking. (Box 48)
- Cohen, Audrey. (Box 48)
- Coins. (Box 48)
- Cold. (Box 48)
- College pranks, hi-jinks. (Box 49)
- College president. (Box 49)
- Colorado River. (Box 49)
- Condors. (Box 49)
- Corneal lens. (Box 49)
- Darrin. (Box 50)
- Death Valley wildlife. (Box 50)
- Deep Sea Divers (Box 50)
  - Pt. Mugu. (Box 50)
  - Sparling school. (Box 50)
- Della Robbia wreaths. (Box 50)
- Dichter, Dr. Everet. (Box 51)
- Disney, Walt. (Box 51)
- Disneyland. (Box 51)
- Dobie, J. Frank. (Box 51)
- Dogs - Array rescue teams parachute. (Box 51)
- Dogs - Ashton races. (Box 52)
- Don Lee. (Box 52)
- Douglas. (Box 52)
- Drive-ins. (Box 52)
- Dreyfuss, Henry. (Box 52)
- Dykstra. (Box 52)
- Eagle Scouts. (Box 52)
- Ears-hearing aids. (Box 53)
- Earthquakes. (Box 53)
- Earth worms. (Box 53)
- Edwards Air Force Base. (Box 53)
- Elliott, Sax. (Box 53)
- Executive secretaries. (Box 54)
- Eyes. (Box 54)
- Eyes - corneal lenses. (Box 54)
- Farm accidents. (Box 54)
- Father "Pat" family theatre. (Box 55)
- Fatigue. (Box 55)
- Fats. (Box 55)
- F.B.I. academy. (Box 55)
- F.B.I. - bad checks. (Box 55)
- Feta farms. (Box 55)
- Feet. (Box 56)
- Fernal. (Box 56)
- Fire - Los Angeles, November 6-9, 1962. (Box 56, Box 57)
- Fire Against fire. (Box 57)
- Fish and game marine patrol. (Box 57)
- Fleas. (Box 57)
- Foreign languages in the elementary schools. (Box 57)
- Food fallacies. (Box 57)
- Football - UCLA. (Box 58)
- Forestry driving. (Box 58)
- Frozen prepared foods. (Box 58)
- Frozen foods. (Box 58)
- Fuller-weights and measures. (Box 59)
- Furseth, Andrew. (Box 59)
- Gage laboratory. (Box 59)
- Gems. (Box 59)
- General atomic. (Box 60)
- General Motors - Santa Barbara. (Box 60)
- Gibberellin. (Box 60)
- Glaucoma. (Box 60)
- Glomar Challenger. (Box 60)
- Gold mining. (Box 61)
- Gophers. (Box 61)
- Gout. (Box 61)
- Gray markets. (Box 61)
- Griffith, D.W. (Box 61)
- Griffith, D.W. - miscellaneous. (Box 61)
- Griseo, Fulvin. (Box 61)
- Grizzly. (Box 61)
- Grunion. (Box 61)
- Guns (Box 61, Box 62)
  - Muzzle loaders. (Box 61)
  - Pfeifer custom made. (Box 62)
- Hahn, Milton E. (Box 62)
- Haley, Robert. (Box 62)
- Hand animals. (Box 62)
- Hands. (Box 62)
- Hanson, Della. (Box 62)
- Hansen, Howard. (Box 63)
- Harmonicas. (Box 63)
- Health professions - career education. (Box 63)
- Happiness. (Box 63)
- Heifetz. (Box 63)
- Height of children. (Box 64)
- Heinemann, Ed. (Box 64)
- Hells Canyon dam. (Box 64)
- Hernia - "One Dag" operation. (Box 64)
- Highways (in California). (Box 64)
- Hines wholesale - nurseries. (Box 65)
- Hoffman - the dynamiter. (Box 65)
- Honeybee bid-analyzer. (Box 65)
- "Hot Box." (Box 65)
- "Hot Rods." (Box 65)
- House movers. (Box 65)
- Houses, engineering of. (Box 65)
- Hydroponics. (Box 65)
- Hydropsychotherapy. (Box 65)
- Hypnotism. (Box 66)
- Ice cream. (Box 66)
- Identi-kit. (Box 66)
- Insects. (Box 66)
- Japanese. (Box 66)
- Jeep clubs - Dune Riders. (Box 66)
- Jet planes. (Box 66)
- Jets - "Seeing Eye." (Box 66)
- Jetton, Walter. (Box 67)
- Jewish farmers. (Box 67)
- Junior colleges. (Box 67)
- Junks. (Box 67)
- Justin boots. (Box 67)
- Kaiser, Henry. (Box 67)
- Kansas rural health plan. (Box 68)
- Katsanevas, Mike. (Box 68)
- KBIG - America's most unique radio station. (Box 68)
- Kelp. (Box 68)
- Kirn, Lou. (Box 68)
- Los Angeles street names. (Box 69)
- Los Angeles superior court. (Box 69)
- Laguna art festival. (Box 69)
- Lakes (desert). (Box 69)
- Levis. (Box 69)
- Libby, Willard F. (Box 69)
- Lightning. (Box 70)
- Limoneira - Lemon Ranch. (Box 70)
- Listen to nature. (Box 70)
- Live bait boat. (Box 70)
- Lockheed. (Box 71)
- Log drive. (Box 71)
- LP-gas. (Box 71)
- Magnetic fluid clutch. (Box 71)
- Magnetometer. (Box 72)
- Malibu. (Box 72)
- Malibu outrigger. (Box 72)
- Marriage - 8 reasons for failure. (Box 72)
- Married students. (Box 72)
- Marshlands (California). (Box 72)
- Marti, Jose. (Box 72)
- McRann, Audrey. (Box 72)
- Mathematics. (Box 73)
- Mayer, Dr. Maria Goeppert. (Box 73)
- Medical schools. (Box 73)
- Men's Garden Club of Los Angeles. (Box 73)
- Metals-light. (Box 73)
- Meteorites. (Box 74)
- Mexico (Box 74, Box 75)
  - Aleman. (Box 74)
  - Archaeology. (Box 74)
  - Arts and crafts. (Box 74)
  - Fishing. (Box 74)
  - Miscellaneous. (Box 74)
  - Petroleum. (Box 75)
  - Silver. (Box 75)
- Middle-aged man. (Box 75)
- Mid-Pacific expedition. (Box 75)
- Migratory labor. (Box 75)
- Milk. (Box 75)
- Miller, Loye Holmes. (Box 75)
- Mission Day. (Box 75)
- Model making. (Box 76)
- Molter, Dorothy. (Box 76)
- Moore, Bergenthal. (Box 76)
- Mormons (Box 76, Box 77)
  - [No further description available]. (Box 76)
  - Brigham Young house. (Box 77)
  - David O. McKay. (Box 77)
  - Indian student placement. (Box 77)
- Moto polo. (Box 77)
- Motorcycle drill team. (Box 77)
- Mozier, Pat. (Box 78)
- MRAK. (Box 78)
- Music of the future. (Box 78)
- National odd shoe exchange. (Box 78)
- (The) Nature Conservancy. (Box 78)
- NC-4 Smokey Rhoads. (Box 78)
- Neighborhoods. (Box 79)
- North American Aviation (Apollo project). (Box 79)
- Northrop. (Box 79)
- NOTS - Naval Ordinance Test Station. (Box 79)
- N-rays. (Box 79)
- Nursery school for visually handicapped children. (Box 79)
- Ocean resources. (Box 80)
- Oceanography. (Box 80)
- Oceanography - Naval history division, June 1965. (Box 80)
- Office buildings. (Box 81)
- Oil well drilling. (Box 81)
- "Oldest house in America." (Box 81)
- Outdoor manners. (Box 81)
- Overhead doors. (Box 81)
- Pacific science board. (Box 81)
- Pal, George. (Box 81)
- Palominos. (Box 82)
- Panel of Americans. (Box 82)
- Pan American highway. (Box 82)
- Panunzio file no.1. (Box 82)
- Panunzio file no.2: TIAA-AAC-AAUP material. (Box 82)
- Paper - "foxing." (Box 83)
- Parsons, Herb. (Box 83)
- Parsons, George Whitwell. (Box 83)
- Peace Corps. (Box 83)
- Pearls. (Box 83)
- Petroleum. (Box 83)
- Phonovision. (Box 83)
- Piñon trees, nuts. (Box 83)
- Plastic surgery. (Box 83)
- Pomona college plan. (Box 83)
- Post office. (Box 83)
- Potrero Canyon. (Box 83)
- Prestressed concrete. (Box 84)
- Prisons in the pines., (3 files) (Box 84, Box 85)
- Profit sharing. (Box 85)
- Profile of a stream. (Box 85)
- Project India. (Box 85)
- Propellors. (Box 85)
- Pygmy forest. (Box 86)
- Rabies. (Box 86)
- Race. (Box 86)
- Radio propagation laboratory. (Box 86)
- RAMAC. (Box 86)
- Rand. (Box 86)
- Reagan task force. (Box 86)
- Rebild National Park. (Box 86)
- Redwoods. (Box 87)
- Retired officers as teachers. (Box 87)
- Revelle, Richard. (Box 87)
- Revelle, Incorporated. (Box 87)
- Reventhlow. (Box 87)
- Revolution on the docks. (Box 88)
- Rio de Janeiro. (Box 88)
- Roberts, Benton. (Box 88)
- Rocketdyne. (Box 88)
- Rockets. (Box 89)
- Rockhounds. (Box 89)
- Rogers, Will-State park. (Box 89)
- Rode. (Box 89)
- Ross, Loos. (Box 89)
- Rubber balls. (Box 89)
- San Diego Bay. (Box 89)
- San Francisco. (Box 90)
- San Jacinto tramway. (Box 90)
- Sanders, Henry. (Box 90)
- Santa Ana winds. (Box 90)
- Santa Monica Mountains. (Box 90)
- Sardines (Scripps). (Box 90)
- Schools of tomorrow. (Box 90)
- Science fortnightly. (Box 91)
- Scripps Institute of Oceanography. (Box 91)
- Sea serphent. (Box 91)
- Seal - Guadalupe Fur. (Box 91)
- Seals. (Box 91)
- Seat belts. (Box 91)
- Self-serve gasoline station. (Box 91)
- Seven deadly sins of wives. (Box 91)
- Shelton - Frank, Dr. Violetta W. (Box 91)
- Shock research unit - IBM, USC. (Box 92)
- "The Silverton" - Denver and Rio Grande narrow guage. (Box 92)
- Skiing. (Box 92)
- Skin. (Box 92)
- Sleep. (Box 93)
- Smell (the sense of). (Box 93)
- Smog. (Box 93)
- Smuggling. (Box 93)
- Snow and ice conditions. (Box 93)
- Southern California (Box 93, Box 94)
  - [No further description available]. (Box 93)
  - Owens Valley, Death Valley. (Box 93)
  - Smog. (Box 93)
  - The Times. (Box 94)
  - Traffic. (Box 94)
  - Water. (Box 94)
- Space. (Box 94)
- Sproul, Robert Gordon. (Box 94)
- Stanford Research Center. (Box 94)
- State Department. (Box 95)
- Stauffer. (Box 95)
- Stein, Jones. (Box 95)
- Stevens, Jay (fire chief inspection program). (Box 95)
- (National) Story League. (Box 95)
- Strother, Ledia (Box 96)
  - "The Day America Gave Me a Flag." (Box 96)
  - "I Bought a Man for $50." (Box 96)
- Students (self-propelled). (Box 96)
- Submarine library. (Box 96)
- Suicide. (Box 96)
- Sun Valley. (Box 96)
- Systems Development Corporation. (Box 96)
- Systemics. (Box 97)
- Team teaching. (Box 97)
- Teeth. (Box 97)
- Telescope - 200 inch. (Box 98)
- Television (Box 98)
  - [No further description available]. (Box 98)
  - Jerry Fairbanks. (Box 98)
  - Frauds. (Box 98)
- Temperament tests. (Box 98)
- Thompson - Ramo-Wooldridge. (Box 98)
- Tides in the earth. (Box 99)
- Traffic police. (Box 99)
- Trail riders. (Box 99)
- Travel with Kids. (Box 99)
- Tree farms. (Box 100)
- Tropical fish. (Box 100)
- Trouble shooting contest. (Box 100)
- Turkeys. (Box 100)
- University of California. (Box 100)
- Tuna. (Box 101)
- Tunnel men. (Box 101)
- Ulcers. (Box 101)
- Ultrasonics. (Box 101)
- Ultrasonics in medicine. (Box 102)
- Ultrasound diagnosis. (Box 102)
- Unbalanced teachers. (Box 102)
- Underground (Box 103)
  - Miscellaneous. (Box 103)
  - Transmission. (Box 103)
  - Technical articles. (Box 103)
- Underwater photography. (Box 104)
- University of California. (Box 104)
- USC medical center. (Box 104)
- U.S. Department of Agriculture (Box 104)
  - Access roads. (Box 104)
  - Bees. (Box 104)
  - Farm machinery. (Box 104)
  - Grass laboratory. (Box 104)
  - Insects. (Box 104)
- U.S. Navy - battleships. (Box 105)
- Vanishing wildlife. (Box 105)
- Vincent Thomas bridge. (Box 105)
- Volleyball. (Box 105)
- Vote tally system (Coleman). (Box 105)
- VSEP - Veteran's Special Education Program. (Box 105)
- Warren, Mrs. Stafford. (Box 106)
- Warts. (Box 106)
- Washington, George (Box 106)
  - [No further description available]. (Box 106)
  - Christmas list. (Box 106)
  - Monument. (Box 106)
- Water. (Box 106)
- Weather. (Box 106)
- Weather and you. (Box 106)
- Weather watchers. (Box 107)
- Weightlifting. (Box 107)
- Welk, Lawrence. (Box 107)
- Weights and measures. (Box 107)
- Whales. (Box 107)
- Whiplash. (Box 107)
- White Mountain Lab. (Box 108)
- Mt. Whitney. (Box 108)
- Wide loads. (Box 108)
- Winter, Clarence. (Box 108)
- Wirespondence. (Box 108)
- Witte, Lou. (Box 108)
- Women who won't get home tonight. (Box 108)
- Wood. (Box 108)
- Whitney. (Box 109)
- Yacht race. (Box 109)
- Young, Floyd D. (Box 109)
- Zebba, Sam. (Box 109)
- World War II victory newspapers. (Box 109)
- U.S. Navy (Box 110, Box 111, Box 112, Box 113)
  - Cruisers. (Box 110)
  - Demolition teams. (Box 110)
  - Mine sweepers. (Box 110)
  - Naval ordinance lab. (Box 110)
  - 16 inch gun. (Box 110)
  - Navy electronics lab. (Box 110)
  - Nimitz. (Box 110)
  - Pacific missile range. (Box 111)
  - Pacific war. (Box 111)
  - Parachutes. (Box 112)
  - Seabees. (Box 112)
  - Service force. (Box 112)
  - SOFAR. (Box 112)
  - Submarines. (Box 112)
  - Torpedoes. (Box 112)
  - Ulithi. (Box 112)
  - Upchuckers. (Box 112)